<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Particle Physics on Dev the dev</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/particle-physics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Particle Physics on Dev the dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 18:47:40 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/particle-physics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kinematic Correlations of Charmed Hadrons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pythia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 18:47:40 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pythia/</guid>
      <description>In my junior year, I took an independent research course under Dr. Deepa Thomas whose work specializes in High Energy Physics and Quark Gluon Plasma. A common research method in this field is to use a Monte Carlo event generator, such as Pythia, to simulate particle collision data at extremely high energy. This post will cover my analysis of the kinematic correlations of charmed hadrons. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t checked out my crash course on particle physics, check it out here, as this post assumes a basic knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to High Energy Physics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/particle_physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 18:47:40 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/particle_physics/</guid>
      <description>Hey guys! This past semester, I dove deep into a research project in Professor Deepa Thomas&amp;rsquo;s lab at UT Austin, where her group specializes in Quark Gluon Plasma (QGP). This post aims to give readers a overview of particle physics theory. After, be sure to give my Pythia studies a read to see how we can use particle collision data to probe at these theories!&#xA;The Standard Model In physics, all known interactions between matter and energy can be attributed to the four fundamental forces of nature.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
